engineers who studied engineering.
los ingenieros que estudiaron ingeniería.
The truth is, these folks are no longer the rule, but the exception. A 2010 study found that only a quarter of college graduates work in a field that relates to their degree. I graduated with not one but two degrees in biology. To my parents' dismay, I am neither a doctor nor a scientist. (Laughter) Years of studying DNA replication and photosynthesis did little to prepare me for a career in technology. I had to teach myself everything from sales, marketing, strategy, even a little programming, on my own. I had never held the title of Product Manager before I sent my resume in to Etsy. I had already been turned down by Google and several other firms and was getting frustrated. The company had recently gone public, so as part of my job application, I read the IPO filings from cover to cover and built a website from scratch which included my analysis of the business and four ideas for new features. It turned out the team was actively working on two of those ideas and had seriously considered a third. I got the job. We all know people who were ignored or overlooked at first but went on to prove their critics wrong. My favorite story? Brian Acton, an engineering manager
La verdad es que ellos ya no son la regla, sino la excepción. Un estudio del 2010 halló que solo un cuarto de los graduados trabaja en un campo relacionado con su carrera. Yo me gradué no con uno sino con dos títulos en biología. Para desazón de mis padres, no soy doctor ni científico. (Risas) Años de estudiar la replicación del ADN y la fotosíntesis poco me prepararon para una carrera en tecnología. Tuve que aprender todo por mi cuenta: ventas, marketing, estrategia, incluso un poco de programación, yo solo. Nunca había tenido el título de Jefe de Producto antes de enviar mi currículo a Etsy. Ya me habían rechazado Google y varias otras compañías y me estaba frustrando. La compañía había entrado al mercado hacía poco, por eso como parte de mi solicitud de trabajo leí su oferta pública inicial de cabo a rabo y diseñé un sitio web desde cero que incluía mi análisis del negocio y cuatro ideas de nuevas funciones. Resultó ser que el equipo estaba trabajando activamente en dos de esas y estaba considerando seriamente otra. Conseguí el empleo. Todos conocemos casos de personas que fueron ignoradas al principio pero terminaron derrotando a los críticos. ¿Mi historia favorita? La de Brian Acton, un gerente de ingeniería
who was rejected by both Twitter and Facebook before cofounding WhatsApp, the mobile messaging platform that would sell for 19 billion dollars. The hiring systems we built in the 20th century are failing us and causing us to miss out on people with incredible potential. The advances in robotics and machine learning and transforming the way we work, automating routine tasks in many occupations while augmenting and amplifying human labor in others. At this rate, we should all be expecting to do jobs we've never done before for the rest of our careers. So what are the tools and strategies we need to identify tomorrow's high performers? In search for answers, I've consulted with leaders across many sectors, read dozens of reports and research papers and conducted some of my own talent experiments. My quest is far from over, but here are three ideas to take forward. One: expand your search. If we only look for talent in the same places we always do -- gifted child programs, Ivy League schools, prestigious organizations -- we're going to get the same results we always have.
rechazado por Twitter y por Facebook antes de cofundar WhatsApp, la aplicación de mensajería móvil que luego se vendió por USD 19 000 millones. La forma de contratar que construimos en el siglo XX nos falla y produce que dejemos ir a personas con un potencial increíble. Los avances en robótica y aprendizaje máquina cambian la forma en que trabajamos, automatizando las tareas rutinarias de muchos trabajos a la vez que aumentan y amplifican la labor humana en otros. A este ritmo, todos deberíamos contar con hacer trabajos que nunca hicimos durante el resto de nuestra carrera. Entonces ¿qué herramientas necesitamos para identificar a los genios del mañana? Buscando respuestas a esta pregunta me comuniqué con líderes de muchos sectores, leí decenas de reseñas y trabajos de investigación y realicé mis propios experimentos sobre el talento. Mi búsqueda está muy lejos de terminar, pero aquí hay tres ideas para tener en cuenta; Uno: expande tu búsqueda. Si solo buscamos talento en los mismos lugares de siempre: escuelas para genios, universidades famosas, organizaciones de prestigio, vamos a obtener los resultados de siempre.
Baseball was transformed when the cash-strapped Oakland Athletics started recruiting players who didn't score highly on traditionally valued metrics, like runs batted in, but who had the ability to help the team score points and win games. This idea is taking hold outside of sports. The Head of Design and Research at Pinterest told me that they've built one of the most diverse and high-performing teams in Silicon Valley because they believe that no one type of person holds a monopoly on talent. They've worked hard to look beyond major tech hubs and focus on designers' portfolios, not their pedigrees. Two: hire for performance. Inspired by my own job experience, I cofounded a hiring platform called Headlight, which gives candidates an opportunity to shine. Just as teams have tryouts and plays have auditions, candidates should be asked to demonstrate their skills before they're hired. Our clients are benefiting from 85 years of employment research, which shows that work samples are one of the best predictors of success on the job. If you're hiring a data analyst, give them a spreadsheet of historical data and ask them for their key insights. If you're hiring a marketing manager,
El béisbol cambió cuando los Atléticos de Oakland, cortos de dinero, empezaron a reclutar jugadores sin altos puntajes por ejemplo de carreras al bate pero que tenían la capacidad de ayudar a su equipo a anotar puntos y ganar. Esta idea está asentándose fuera del deporte. Un ejecutivo de Pinterest me dijo que han construido uno de los equipos más diversos y productivos de Silicon Valley porque piensan que no solo un tipo de persona tiene un monopolio sobre el talento. Se fuerzan a ver más allá de los lugares tradicionales y se enfocan en el portfolio del diseñador no en su pedigrí. Dos: contrata por desempeño. Inspirado por mi propia experiencia laboral, cofundé una plataforma de contratación llamada Headlight, que les da a los candidatos una oportunidad de brillar. Tal como las obras de teatro tienen ensayos, a los candidatos se les pide que demuestren su talento antes de ser contratados. El cliente se beneficia de 85 años de investigación sobre contratación, que señalan a las pruebas como uno de los mejores predictores de éxito laboral. ¿Quieres a un analista de datos? Dale una planilla con datos históricos y pregúntale qué puede determinar. ¿Buscas a un jefe de marketing?
have them plan a launch campaign for a new product. And if you're a candidate, don't wait for an employer to ask. Seek out ways to showcase your unique skills and abilities outside of just the standard resume and cover letter. Three: get the bigger picture. I've heard about recruiters who are quick to label a candidate a job-hopper based on a single short stint on their resume; read about professors who are more likely to ignore identical messages from students because their name was black or Asian instead of white. I was almost put on a special needs track as a child. A month into kindergarten, my teacher wrote a page-long memo noting that I was impulsive, had a short attention span, and despite my wonderful curiosity, I was exhausting to work with. (Laughter)
Hazlo planear una campaña de lanzamiento. Y si eres un candidato, no esperes que un empleador te lo pida. Busca una forma de demostrar tus capacidades y talentos más allá de tu currículo y carta de presentación. Tres: ten una visión general. He escuchado de reclutadores que califican a alguien de poco comprometido por tan solo un trabajo donde estuvo poco tiempo; he leído sobre profesores que ignoran aplicaciones idénticas de estudiantes porque sus nombres son asiáticos o afroestadounidenses en vez de blancos. Yo casi termino en un lugar para niños especiales. A un mes de entrar a kindergarten, mi maestra escribió una larga nota que decía que era impulsivo, tenía un período de atención corto, y que a pesar de mi maravillosa curiosidad, era cansador trabajar conmigo. (Risas)
The principal asked my parents into a meeting, asked my mother if there had been complications at birth and suggested I meet with a school psychologist. My father saw what was happening and quickly explained our family situation. As recent immigrants, we lived in the attic of a home that cared for adults with mental disabilities. My parents worked nights to make ends meet, and I had little opportunity to spend time with kids my own age. Is it really a surprise that an understimulated five-year-old boy might be a little excited in a kindergarten classroom after an entire summer by himself? Until we get a holistic view of someone, our judgment of them will always be flawed. Let's stop equating experience with ability, credentials with competence. Let's stop settling for the safe, familiar choice and leave the door open for someone who could be amazing. We need employers to let go of outdated hiring practices and embrace new ways of identifying and cultivating talent, and candidates can help by learning to tell their story in powerful and compelling ways. We could live in a world where people are seen for what they're truly capable of and have the opportunity to realize their full potential. So let's go out and build it. Thank you. (Applause)
El director llamó a mis padres a una reunión, le preguntó a mi madre si había sido un parto complicado y sugirió que me viera con el psicólogo del kindergarten. Mi padre vio lo que pasaba y le explicó nuestra situación familiar. Como inmigrantes recientes, vivíamos en el ático de un asilo de ancianos con discapacidades mentales. Mis padres trabajaban mucho para mantenernos, y yo tenía pocas oportunidades de pasar tiempo con chicos de mi edad. ¿Era entonces una sorpresa que un chico de 5 años con pocos estímulos se emocionara un poco en un salón lleno de niños después de pasar todo un verano solo? Hasta que no tengamos una visión global de alguien, nuestros juicios sobre esa persona siempre van a estar errados. Dejemos de igualar experiencia con capacidad, credenciales con competencia. Dejemos de conformarnos con la opción segura y familiar y dejemos la puerta abierta para alguien que puede ser genial. Necesitamos que los empleadores abandonen las prácticas anticuadas y adopten nuevas formas de identificar y cultivar el talento, y los candidatos pueden ayudar aprendiendo a contar su historia de una forma fuerte y atractiva. Podemos vivir en un mundo en el que veamos a las personas por lo que pueden hacer, en el que tengan la oportunidad de lograr su máximo potencial. Así que vayamos a construirlo. Gracias. (Aplausos)